Paulo Manfre

Apartment 633 King Edwards Wharf, 25 Sheepcote St, Birmingham, B16 8FX paulo manfre@hotmail.com 07561 583699

Personal Statement

During my 12 years of experience in finance and accounting area I've always been involved in developing tools and reports to analyse data and transform it into useful information. For that reason, I am looking for an opportunity to pivot my career and dedicate myself exclusively into studying and working data analysis.

Main Skills

- Native Portuguese speaker, EU passport and right to work in UK.
- Analytical thinker
- Microsoft Office (Advanced Excel, Word and Access).
- SAP Finance
- Attention to detail and accuracy.
- Team worker
- Adaptable to different working environments.

Employment History

STK Energy Systems - Brazil - March 2021 to September 2021 – Temporary Contract Controller Analyst

Working alongside the financial manager and director to provide financial reports. I was responsible for accounting, reporting, analysis, budgeting, and forecasting for electrical substation projects. Also oversaw accounts receivable, accounts payable, payroll, inventory and compliance.

OCS Group - UK - February 2019 to November 2020 Cleaner

I worked as a cleaner at the NEC while seeking work that uses my professional experience and to help with the development of my written and spoken English.

I maintained Health and Safety standards at all times and deal with any customer requests.

Grace School - Brazil - March 2018 to September 2018

Financial Consultant

Financial consultant to the School. I assisted in the creation of the finance department and financial processes. Set up ERP within the school and trained staff in using the system prior to moving to UK.

Imtep - Brazil - October 2017 to May 2018 Bid Writer

I constructed proposals for the supply of occupational health services to large companies. I helped secure contracts with FIAT, Volkswagen, Renault and Petrobras.

Votorantim Construction Group - Brazil - August 2012 to September 2017 Accounting Analyst - November 2014 to September 2017

I provided financial advice and information to Business Units in Brazil, including monthly calculation, payment declarations, accounting reconciliations of VAT and reporting on performance indicators for the business.

Main Results Achieved:

- Significant reduction in accounting pendency.
- Recovery of Fiscal Credits from central Government in challenging circumstances.
- Implementation of Performance Indicators across 217 factories.

Accounting Analyst in Continuous Improvement - October 2013 to November 2014 I supported the implementation of change processes as part of the Continuous Improvement team. I used tools including PDCA, Kaizen, Ishikawa and A3 to improve financial performance and decision making within the company.

Main Results Achieved:

- Worked to prevent and correct process flaws generating savings of R\$1m.
- Created financial productivity tools.
- Creation of KPI's.

Accounting Analyst - August 2012 to October 2013

I was responsible for accounting reconciliation for the retained taxes account and providing support to companies from the Votorantim Group, including monthly calculation and payment of payroll, tax and delivery of government report on 25,000 employees.

Ergoclin Occupational Health - Brazil - February 2011 to March 2012 **Team Leader**

I managed a team of two, with responsibility for accounts payable, accounts receivable, banking conciliation, invoicing, budget and forecast cash flow. I prepared financial reports for the board of directors, maintained the financial spreadsheets for the company and supported the customer service area and commercial departments.

Main Results Achieved:

- 20% increase in income in one month.
- Recovery of defaults in the amount of R\$ 80kin a 40-day period.
- 7% reduction in operational costs.
- Implementation of financial indicators.

Employer Human Resources - Brazil - May 2010 to October 2010 Human Resources Officer

I was responsible for the audit of payroll and Brazilian tax regulations. I developed and implemented the operational system for payroll, accounting and finance Webfopag for over 1,000 employees.

First Baptist Church - Brazil - March 2009 to December 2009 Financial Analyst

I developed the financial system for the Church, including setting up processes for accounts payable, banking conciliation, future payments, budget forecasting and tax collection. I managed the financial system, including creating financial reports for the Board of Directors.

Uati - Brazil - December 2008 to February 2009

Mathematical Assistant

I was responsible to prepare the mathematical calculations and legal expertise to review contractual values in the Housing and Labour Financing System area, and also providing the clarification to support the Law Firms in Justice.

Education

BSC In Business Administration

Covered general business administration, including HR, with main focus on finance. Universidades Curitiba (Brazil) - Curitiba July 2006 to December 2010

BA in Physical Education

Faculdade Dom Bosco (Brazil) – Curitiba July 2003 to June 2006

Languages

Spanish: Intermediate reading and basic speaking and writing.

Portuguese: Native.